Challa Divya

Mobile: 6304367615

Email: challadivya2000@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/challa-divya-0959951b3

Summary

Seeking a challenging and rewarding opportunity with an organization of repute which recognizes my true potential and effectively utilizes my excellent analytical skills in developing your company. An active professional with 1 year of experience in IT industry with focus on Data Analysis

Technical Skills

- Java
- Spring Data JPA
- Azure Data Bricks
- MySQL /PLSQL
- Azure Data Factory
- Spring MVC Basics
- Python
- Problem-solving

Experience

Programmer Analyst

Cognizant Technology Solutions, Bangalore(12/2023-current)

Programmer Analyst Trainee

Cognizant Technology Solutions, Bangalore (12/2022 – 11/2023)

Programmer Analyst Trainee (Intern)

Cognizant, Hyderabad (remote) (03/2022 – 06/2022)

Trained on the technologies like MySQL, ETL tool - Informatica PowerCenter, etc. Completely transformed the data from different sources like the flat files (csv and txt), MySql DB, Oracle DB by applying the transformations in the Informatica PowerCenter as the user requirement. A sophisticated data processing has been done on the input data which was given in different forms. Finally, delivered that data into the Data warehouse.

Personal Projects

Curd operations Using Spring MVC

• In this project I created a Simple Rest API For Employees using Spring Data JPA, Mysql database to perform basic CURD operations Using Postman.

Employee Registration Form Using Spring boot.

• In this Project I created a Simple Registration Form Using MySQL for storing Employee details and where user can perform basic CURD Operations

Accomplishments

Cleared the HackerRank's Basic SQL certificate assessment

Certifications

- Completed Python Course at Course Era
- Completed Informatica Power Center at Udemy
- Completed the Oracle SQL BootCamp(2023) at Udemy
- Completed Databricks &Spark For Data Engineers

Educational Qualification

- B.Tech in Electrical and Electronics CGPA: 8.43 (2018-2022)
- Intermediate in MPC 95.7 (2016-2018)

Languages

- English
- Telugu